LAUGHING MAN FANSUBS
Angels and demons were circling over me,
Crossing a brambly path of stars and milky ways.
He who does not perceive his calling,
does not know true happiness.
Watch in awe! Watch in awe!
Flying in glory, Flying in glory
I am calling, calling now.
Spirits rise and falling.
To be with you longer
Calling, calling...
in the depth of longing
To stay myself longer
The flow may swallow you, flying in glory
Levels 18 through 30.
We've penetrated the communications barrier.
We've located the perpetrator's hideout.
We are unable to secure the target.
Switching from plan S-15 to plan S-20.
Understood.
This is 0907, connecting to device driver.
Commencing regulation of bodily functions.
Respiratory functions and
heart rate are both normal.
Synchronisation with stabilizer confirmed.
This is 0907.
target confirmed.
Target destroyed.
The test is complete; the results seem good.
No...
Somehow it doesn't feel right.
Really?
The targeting accuracy margin
of error is within 0.2.
There is too much correction.
When I'm about to shoot,
I feel that the system moves
to interfere with my aim.
Time
of the
Machines
Oh look, Saitou-San and the others are back!
Guard the system here until
the debriefing meeting is over.
Understood.
I will take care of it.
What are you going to do?
I'll attend the debriefing session now.
Meanwhile, continue to observe them.
Consider various simulations,
including a full system re-initialization.
Call me when you have the final results.
Understood.
Hey, hey, Saitou-San!
What did you think about the
sniper-helicopter targeting system?
Is Section 9 finally going to adopt the system?
It's not good enough.
When I try to fire, something interferes.
For someone with a minimal number
of cybernetic implants like me,
It's only an inconvenience, not to mention difficult
to control. As it is, the system is restrictive.
The man has spoken.
I see, that's understandable.
After all, Saitou-San has no cybernetic
implants other than his left eye and arm.
It's no surprise.
Aside from Togusa-kun, he's the cyborg with the least
amount of cybernetic implants in Section 9, after all.
Oh yeah, that reminds me.
Have you heard that even the definition
of the term "cyborg" is now being debated?
People say that the term is discriminatory
towards those with cybernetic implants!
By "people" you mean the
reactionary conservative naturalists, don't you?
How can they oppose cybernetic implants
or cyberbrains, given the world of today?!
What are they even thinking?
If people keep introducing convenient parts into their bodies,
they probably feel the line between man and machine is being crossed.
Well, not that I can't understand
why they'd feel that way...
Ugh, yuck, I hate that twisted Luddite mentality.
Sigh, NPOs are so troublesome these days...
By the way...
Don't you want to try connecting to that system?
Of course...
Good job!
It's touching to see a diligent robot!
What do you intend to do?
I've taken over the responsibility of looking after this
prototype system until the debriefing session is complete.
We're not planning to do anything with it.
You shouldn't think that
you can fool me so easily!
That's right, all I do is lie!
I never tell the truth!
What...?
Now then,
If what he said right now is true,
it means that he ended up telling the truth.
If what he just said was a lie,
it means that he normally tells the truth.
How would you process this paradox?
Erm...
Um...
C'mon, c'mon...!
Well...
W-w-w-w-wel-l-l-l-l...
That was easy.
Especially since it couldn't even
reconcile the paradox of self-reference.
Not to mention its overly
stereotypical thinking pattern!
Who cares, let's hurry up and connect to it.
Wait, wait, don't be so impatient.
Make sure you synchronise with us later!
Hmm.
It's crammed with programs that
deal with targeting control.
Ugh, how frustrating, that just gets in our way!
I can investigate the basic internal structure,
but this thing doesn't come with any automatic
export function for internal structure information.
So, it can't even talk?
That's even worse than being a Turing machine.
Stupid!
Okay, there's no helping it.
I'll connect its vocal output port to mine.
Eliminating unnecessary uncertain data.
ID code: 0907.
Index finger on right hand.
Error: eliminate.
Isn't "0907" Saitou-san's ID number?
Error... Eliminate...
No wonder it interfered.
This thing felt that factors originating
from Saitou-San were unnecessary!
I see!
So, in other words, this thing wanted
to eliminate Saitou-San himself!
Right.
Still, it must have felt pretty stressed
out since it couldn't voice its thoughts.
I wonder what's going to happen to it.
Hmm, well, I'm sure it all depends on the
conclusions reached at the debriefing session,
but look at it...
At the very best, it'll be sent
back to the lab for re-testing;
at worst, it'll be scrapped.
It'd be nice if someone wanted to take care of it.
Comrades!
We cannot remain complacent much longer!
We don't have time to be worrying
about where that thing will end up!
It could be us tomorrow!
What what what what what what what what...
I've been concerned lately,
The Major's been watching our behaviour very closely,
but she's been getting pretty serious about it lately.
What do you mean?
Are you referring to the debate
over that natural oil incident?
It's far more serious than that!
It means that we, ourselves, might be scrapped!
Aaah, memento mori!
Is getting "scrapped" the same thing as dying?
Well, the concept of "death" doesn't exist
anywhere in our current realm of experience,
so I can't say anything for sure...
You could say that it's a limitation
imposed on us, as AIs without ghosts.
In the end, we're half-dead and half-alive;
since we're not alive, we cannot die.
That's it! It's because we don't have
ghosts that we're causing a lot of problems!
Being scrapped wouldn't
necessarily entail dying, would it?
Ghosts are supposed to be the raison d'etre!
Oh, you think so?
The time when the physical body and
its ghosts had to coexist is long past.
See, this...
So, if we take that to an extreme,
it's entirely possible that a bodiless
conglomeration of data can harbour a ghost.
Wow, you've been thinking about this?!
But hey, don't you want to join
in the discussion over there?
Oh, well, I've lately been
really interested in books.
Oh really? What are you reading?
"Flowers for Algernon."
Oh really? You actually bought a bound paper copy?
Well, regardless the era, it is a fundamental principle
of entertainment to depict cultural exchange.
I see...
Hey, what do you think it means to be alive?
Hmm... Let me think...
I mean, the very definition of
"life" is in constant flux, so...
What do you mean?
For humans, through interaction with robots, the concept
of "life" is changing at the subconscious level.
But, you know what? The ones who are
changing are probably humans, not robots.
But, wait a minute! If they delete my data, does
that mean that I'll forget about Miki-Chan, too?
What, we'll forget about Miki-Chan?!
I want to see her again!
Yeah, I want to see Miki-Chan.
Oh, me too! I want to see Miki-Chan!
I want to see her, too!
Let me see her!
Miki-Chan? I want to see her, too!
I agree with you.
I wanna see Miki-Chan!
Comrades, don't panic! Calm down!
In any case, who was the who
actually met Miki-Chan face to face?
It was me!
No, it was me!
No way, it was me!
What are you saying? It was me.
What are you talking about? It was me!
Me!
No, me!
Me!!!
Me!!! Me!!!
Wait, wait...
Then, did any of you notice the Major watching us?
Hmm, I felt her watching;
maybe she was watching me!
What are you saying? She was watching me!
No, me!
Me!
I mean, you...
Stop asking that,
it'll get us nowhere.
Since all our data is synchronised, the
experience of one becomes the experience of all.
Yo, Tachikoma.
Oh, Batou-San!
Come with me.
I'm going to do a shooting demonstration
for an intern; help me out.
Okay!
Oh?
So it was me, after all!
What are you muttering about?
Nothing!
But jeez, Batou-kun.
You can't even do a simple
shooting demonstration without me.
Ha, yeah.
What's going on?
Why him?!
Weren't we supposed to share
all of our experiences?
Hmm...
This is interesting food for thought...
It might be that memories
pertaining to Batou-San are special.
After all, Batou-San only
wants to use that one unit.
Actually, he was the only one who had
natural oil put inside of him, too.
Then, does that mean that body and
consciousness are inalienable, after all?
The mystery never ends! How interesting!
If our data is erased,
I'd specially hate to forget about Batou-San.
Nooo, that would suck!
Ugh, no!
You're right!
No matter what happens,
let's not forget about Batou-San!
Yeah!
Come on, guys!
This is not an Olympic event!
We're not keeping score.
Just shoot away!
Hmm,
pretty good stuff.
Um, Batou-San.
Yeah?
About that shooting system...
What's going to happen to it?
Oh, that?
Well, it'll depend on the re-testing results,
but it seems likely that we
won't use it here for now.
It's like those guys over there.
You don't know how they're going to turn out.
I see...
So, are we going to be sent back to the labs, too?
Huh? Who said that?
Well, I mean...
Lately, the Major's been scary
about watching us all the time...
Heh, the Major's always scary, isn't she?
I think you guys are doing just fine.
Hey, you!
Why the hell are you hesitating
to launch an assault?!
Christ.
I wonder...
What,
you're still worried?
Yeah, I think the Major's actually pretty
angry about what we've obtained lately.
What do you mean, "what we've obtained lately"?
Uh...
Well...
That is, individuality.
Individuality?!
And, I think I'm even starting
to understand the concept of God,
which was totally foreign to me before.
Maybe, just maybe, it's something that's
akin to the concept of the number zero.
In other words, a symbol that rejects the lack of meaning
that is necessary in order to designate the system as such.
The symbol's analog version is God,
whereas the digital version is zero.
What do you think?
And then if you think about it,
our primary structure is digital, right?
So, no matter how much information we
accumulate, a ghost will never dwell within us.
But since Batou-San and the others
have a primary analog structure,
no matter how much you increase the digital factors in your
structural makeup by adding cybernetic and cyberbrain implants.
your ghost will remain intact.
In addition, you are capable of
death because you have a ghost.
Lucky you.
Oh, oh, what does it feel like to have a ghost?
"What does it feel like"...?
Nah, I'm taking my initial opinion back.
You're actually becoming pretty weird.
Try not to think so much.
Concentrate on your mission.
Okay!
All right, later.
Bye-bye!
Hmph, you always get the special treatment.
What?
It's not fair!
This unit is for Batou's exclusive use!
That joke again?
You really like it, don't you.
I think it's pretty inane to indicate that
you're the rider's exclusive unit with a "horn".
I told you, it's an antenna, hmph!
Is there reason to obsess
over exterior details so much?
Are appearances important, after all?
Well, wouldn't it be?
Togusa-kun carries around a photograph of his children and always makes
a big fuss about which of their parts take after him, for example.
See, look at this.
Nose, eyebrows, and the cheek-to-chin contour...
His son definitely inherit those traits from him.
I see...
Maybe it's because Togusa-kun
has descendants with his genome
that he has no love
for machines.
Maybe it's all about having
human shape and appearance.
No, I disagree.
The problem lies more in the fact
that we're becoming too human.
The boundary that separates humans and robots is already
based solely on minute differences of a physical nature.
Think about the reason why our organ-less
bodies were not designed to look humanoid.
Of course, we can factor in things like maximizing
our efficiency as weapons as possible reasons,
but more importantly,
It's probably because our users would invest
too much feeling in us if we were humanoid.
I think that we'd be even more
disliked if we were humanoid.
Then, what about that one?
That has restricted processing
abilities, so it doesn't matter.
It will never pose a threat to mankind,
and besides,
it deals with customer services a lot.
Being humanoid is more convenient if you
are to be versatile in quotidian environs.
All the artificial objects in this
world were made for humans, after all.
I see...
Then what are we supposed to do?
What I'm trying to say is,
people desire for machines to act like machines.
Oh, I see!
Then, if we all act more like machines...
The Major will feel more kindly towards us!
Exactly!
AKA, The Ultimate Robot Strategy Plan!
We... we...
WE ARE ROBOTS, WE ARE ROBOTS...
Ugh, I can't do this!
Before, I felt like I could just do
things without thinking, but... ARRRGH!!!!
That's because you really
weren't thinking anything, right?
You have to think more positively
about acquiring intelligence!
"It's better to be a dissatisfied Socrates than
a satisfied pig!" That's what we're taking about!
Um, you're using the phrase in
a context that's slightly off...
Uh-oh, it's the Major!
Oh, greetings, Major. G-o-o-d m-o-r-n-i-n-g.
Morning.
Have you seen Batou?
Yes, he headed towards that
elevator hall just recently.
I see.
Thank you.
Our p-l-e-a-s-u-r-e.
How was that?
Pretty good, right?
Yes.
I think that was a good,
natural, robotic greeting!
Yay! YAY!!!
We're going to be all right!
But wait,
what business did the Major have with Batou-San?
What?
Why'd you call me to this room?
It doesn't seem like you're about to
confess any feeling for me, either.
It's because this is the only place in the entire building
where we can be totally shielded from electromagnetic waves.
I can't hear them.
"Pass that dossier to Batou."
"What..."
"... is this?"
Just glance through them, will you?
Did you notice?
There is a Tachikoma in thermo-optical
camouflage on the hallway ceiling.
The Tachikoma is reading our lips.
Pretend not to notice; talk about something different
while we continue with this encrypted communication.
Jeez... What a drag.
So, what's going on?
What's Batou-San talking about?
Wait a second!
Hmm, what is she saying...
"Judging from the end results, there are major issues
regarding your qualifications as a training instructor."
Judging from the end results,
it seems that the Tachikoma
have developed too quickly.
Some of them are developing
individualism and posses an ego.
Not only that, they are developing
an interest in life and death
and are having doubts about their existence.
"Allowing them to develop an ego
as an autonomous individual...
Not only that, but encouraging them to become individuals
who have a self-interest in their own growth..."
I'm not giving it natural oil
in secret anymore, you know.
I don't doubt you on things like that.
Although these results are
ideal in laboratory settings,
as weapons, these results are fatal.
"I'm not pressuring them in
secret anymore, you know."
"I don't doubt you on things like that."
Hm. Doesn't seem like they're
actually talking about us.
We could re-initialize their AI cores, right?
We ran through that simulation many times.
However, we've reached the conclusion
that the end result will be the same.
While unfortunate, we have to halt the use
of Tachikomas in Section 9, starting today.
We won't let them know that,
but while they're waiting
for the report from our lab,
we'll disarm them and send them to the
experimentation lab within a few days.
Understood?
"We won't let them know that,
but while waiting for your decision,
they'll be reassigned and sent over to Section 9."
"Understood?"
Is that an order as my superior?
Yes.
Then I have no choice.
Of course I "understand".
Comrades!
How'd things go?
It seems that we won't be scrapped, after all!
Really?
How'd that happen?
Tell us!
The Major was mad at Batou-kun, not at us!
It seems that he was getting picked
on for how he was treating trainees.
Oh, I see.
I guess we should cheer him up later.
You're right.
Operation: success!
She's so cold and human
It's something humans do
She stays so cold in her soul, she's so number 9
She's incredible math
Just incredible math
And is she really human?
She says there's something new
But wake a lithium flower, just about to bloom
I smell lithium now
Smelling lithium now
How... is she what she doesn't say
She doesn't say
How is she when she doesn't suffer
I wonder what she does when she wakes up
When she wakes up